http://www.perio.org/privacy.htm

Search form
Search
You are hereHome » Contact Us » AAP Privacy Statement
In this section:
Effective Date: May 25, 2018
The American Academy of Periodontology (AAP) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it at all times. This online privacy statement explains how the AAP collects, uses and safeguards information on its website, www.perio.org (“website” or “site”). This Internet Privacy Statement applies only to information collected by the AAP through its website.
Information Collection and Use
When you browse perio.org and do not interact with the site for any online service or product, you browse anonymously. IP addresses (unique numbers assigned by Internet Services Providers to every computer on the Internet) are used to analyze trends, administer the site, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use, but IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.
When you interact with our site in some way, such as subscribing to an AAP publication, purchasing an AAP product, applying for AAP membership, participating in online surveys, submitting questions or comments or requesting information or materials, we will collect certain personal information from you. The type of personal information collected will vary but includes name, address, phone number, billing and delivery information, email address, and other demographic information. When payment is required for a product or service, the purchaser will be asked to enter credit card information on a secure payment site.
The provision of personally identifiable information is sometimes required by law and at other times is a result of a contractual requirement. You may be required to provide personally identifiable information, for example in a case where we sign a contract with you, and the non-provision of information could, in certain circumstances, prevent a transaction from concluding.
Once collected, we use your personally identifiable information to register you for programs and services you have requested, fulfill your order or application, answer your emailed or online requests, or process surveys. Email addresses and other personal information of site visitors are not provided or released to a third party without the visitor's expressed permission.
We do not use automatic decision-making or engage in profiling.
Where we intend to process your personally identifiable information for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was collected, we will provide you with information regarding the purpose for the processing, as well as other relevant information, prior to processing your personally identifiable information for the new purpose.
Cookies
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about the user. The only usage of cookies on the AAP site is to give AAP members access to password-protected pages after they log in. Cookies are essential for site administration and security.
Sharing
Third-party service providers are used to process Annual Meeting registrations, ship orders that are placed online, assist with our customer services, and manage contact and correspondence with members. These companies are instructed neither to retain, share, store nor use personal information for other purposes. We may share personal information with other affiliated organizations or entities, in connection with events. We may disclose personal information to third parties in order to protect the legal rights, safety, and security of AAP, our members, or other persons; enforce our legal terms; prevent fraud (or for risk management purposes); and comply with or respond to law enforcement or legal process or a request for cooperation by a government or other entity, whether or not legally required.
If we sell all or part of our business, or make a sale or transfer of assets, or are otherwise involved in a merger or business transfer, or in the event of bankruptcy, we may transfer personal information to one or more third parties as part of that transaction.
We may share personal information about you with third parties when you consent to such sharing.
INTERNATIONAL VISITORS
This section applies to those that visit our website from the European Economic Area or Switzerland.
AAP processes personally identifiable information with your consent (e.g., when AAP processes personally identifiable information to provide goods and services you request, such as an AAP newsletter to which you subscribe).
On other occasions, AAP may process personally identifiable information when it needs to do this to fulfill a contract (for example, to process membership applications) or where required to do this by law.
If necessary, AAP may also process personally identifiable information when it is in AAP’s legitimate interests to do this (e.g., for customer service or to administer membership benefits) and when these interests are not overridden by your data protection rights. Please be aware that the personally identifiable information we collect may be transferred to and maintained on servers or databases located outside your state, province, country, or other jurisdiction, where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your location. If you are located outside of the United States, please be advised that we process and store personal information in the United States. In most instances, we transfer data because you enter into a contract with us and the transfer is necessary for the performance of that contract, or with your consent.
You have a right to the following:
To request access to the personally identifiable information we hold about you;
To request that we rectify or erase your personally identifiable information;
To request that we restrict or block the processing of your personally identifiable information;
Under certain circumstances, to receive personally identifiable information about you that we store and transmit to another without hindrance from us, including requesting that we provide your personally identifiable information directly to another, i.e., a right to data portability; and
Where we previously obtained your consent, to withdraw consent to processing your personally identifiable information.
To exercise these rights, contact us using the “Contact Us” section below. Please be aware that AAP may be unable to afford these rights to you under certain circumstances, such as if we are legally prevented from doing so.
Additionally, you have the right to lodge a complaint against us. To do so, contact the supervisory authority in your country of residence.
RETENTION
We will process and store your personally identifiable information only for the period necessary to achieve the purpose of the storage, or as permitted by law. The criteria used to determine the period of storage of information is the respective statutory retention period or as provided in our data retention and destruction policy. After expiration of that period, the corresponding information is routinely deleted, as long as it is no longer necessary for the fulfillment of a contract or the initiation of a contract.
Links to other sites
This website contains links to other sites. The AAP is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.
Security
This website takes every precaution to protect information provided by users. Sensitive information such as credit card numbers is collected only at a secure site that is PCI compliant protecting sensitive cardholder data and maintaining the security of data during transmission as well as stored data.
Site and Service Updates
The AAP sends its members periodic site and service update announcements. Members may request the removal of their names from the member email list.
Contact Us
If you have questions, comments, or concerns about this privacy statement, please contact us, in our role as data controller, at:
privacy@perio.org
Members Only Content: Not Member Only
Find a Periodontist
Zip Code
City
Last Name
Advanced Search and International»
Select Language
Select LanguageEnglishAfrikaansAlbanianAmharicArabicArmenianAzerbaijaniBasqueBelarusianBengaliBosnianBulgarianCatalanCebuanoChichewaChinese (Simplified)Chinese (Traditional)CorsicanCroatianCzechDanishDutchEsperantoEstonianFilipinoFinnishFrenchFrisianGalicianGeorgianGermanGreekGujaratiHaitian CreoleHausaHawaiianHebrewHindiHmongHungarianIcelandicIgboIndonesianIrishItalianJapaneseJavaneseKannadaKazakhKhmerKoreanKurdish (Kurmanji)KyrgyzLaoLatinLatvianLithuanianLuxembourgishMacedonianMalagasyMalayMalayalamMalteseMaoriMarathiMongolianMyanmar (Burmese)NepaliNorwegianPashtoPersianPolishPortuguesePunjabiRomanianRussianSamoanScottish GaelicSerbianSesothoShonaSindhiSinhalaSlovakSlovenianSomaliSpanishSudaneseSwahiliSwedishTajikTamilTeluguThaiTurkishUkrainianUrduUzbekVietnameseWelshXhosaYiddishYorubaZulu
Recent Press Releases
Study: Dental Practices Effective in Preventing Spread of COVID-19
American Academy of Periodontology Stresses the Importance of Periodontal Health during COVID-19
American Academy of Periodontology, SUNSTAR Announce 2019 Innovation Grant Recipients
©2020 American Academy of Periodontology. All rights reserved.
737 N. Michigan Ave., Suite 800, Chicago, IL 60611312-787-5518
Privacy Policy
AAP Foundation       American Board of Periodontology
